<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shopspring + HiveMind</title>
    <description>Designs for Shopspring
</description>
    <link>http://hivemind.works/shopspring/shopspring/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://hivemind.works/shopspring/shopspring/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 20:08:57 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 20:08:57 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Team Page design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After meeting on wednesday, I began mapping out what elements would make for a successful team page. The goals for page, as outlined by Vivi are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;show the value of the team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;show how the team is organized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent some time thinking about the headspace of individuals that would visit the team page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Do I want to work at Spring?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Who would I work with?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“What would my responsibilities be?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these goals and use cases in mind, I made a list of elements that would help answer them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;elements&quot;&gt;Elements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mission Statement
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;sell people on the goal&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a “we’re hiring” callout, with a button to redirect to open positions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;blurb on how awesome the team is
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;backgrounds&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;diversity stats?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Org Dept Navigation
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Blurb about different departments, if selected&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team members
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;bios&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;photos&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;header&quot;&gt;Header&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t want to go the typical route with a large splash image, which I think is overdone, often stagnant, and competes with the copy for attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To draw people to interact with the page, I’d like to add animations to the icons, similar to the old &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thestarvedblog.co.za/whud-up/badass-blog-formfiftyfive-com/&quot;&gt;Form Fifty Five header&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I tested other layouts, I think 1 column centered approach works best for this typ of page. It degrades most elegantly on mobile, maintains a singular focus, and allows the grid to stay above the fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/shopspring/img/team/team-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;team head&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;Grid&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent much of my time working out the besst way to display the team members. Though the list Spring uses currently works well from desktop to mobile, the affordances for interaction and play a grid provides seemed more valuable than a list to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then began playing with the ways the grid could be executed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department sub-nav would remain sticky at the top of the page, and if a specific team was selected, a blurb on that teams resposibilities would appear directly beneath the sub-nav.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we use an orthoganal grid of images, my first idea for a ‘finger’ was to mimic the brady bunch title sequence, having the team members follow the mouse around. I know I could pull this off in a perfomant way, but it would mean that each team member would need 6 pictures (looking straight, up, up-left, left, down-left, down. up-left, left, and down-left could be mirrored). I’d be happy to make a prototype using headshots of myself, if you’re interested in pursuing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/shopspring/img/team/team-grid-info.png&quot; alt=&quot;team head&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second idea was to keep the typical grid, but swap the squares for circles, then add an interaction that draws people to explore, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://v2.desandro.com/articles/undulate/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/shopspring/img/team/team-circles-grid.png&quot; alt=&quot;team head&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/shopspring/img/team/team-circles-grid-hover.png&quot; alt=&quot;team head&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this grid, I think we should have the final team member slot be something like this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/shopspring/img/team/grid-last-item.png&quot; alt=&quot;team head&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;footer&quot;&gt;Footer&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should be the reward for scrolling to the bottom of the team page? Another call out to see open positions? or maybe here is the place for the full page splash image, with a more prominent “Life at Spring” button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my first take:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/shopspring/img/team/team-footer.png&quot; alt=&quot;team footefooter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the changes to the implementation &lt;a href=&quot;/shopspring/iterations/team-1.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;progress&quot;&gt;Progress&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More button&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Account buttons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Styleguide refinement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;next&quot;&gt;Next&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;team page footer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;implement header icons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;implement interactive grid&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;add real content to team page&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;begin careers/engineering page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;modal work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 12:18:45 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://hivemind.works/shopspring/shopspring/jekyll/update/2015/04/29/team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hivemind.works/shopspring/shopspring/jekyll/update/2015/04/29/team.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Navigation Work: header/footer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I began work by reviewing the PSDs Eli had been working on, and cross referencing them with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0BwNoUKizWBdnTG50SzB2MVhQWDg/view&quot;&gt;site map document&lt;/a&gt; Lisa shared with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Determine which links would appear in both the signed in and signed out views&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make/test assumptions on which links are more heirarchically important&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by familiarizing myself with the site map and deciding which links/pages were most heirachical. Displaying every endpoint in the header would be a poor solution, so I narrowed the scope to the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;primary&quot;&gt;Primary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For Brands&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;About&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;secondary&quot;&gt;Secondary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blog&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagine that +90% of visitors will be users/customers/brands, which created the framework to choose the primary links. The secondary links are the ones I thought deserved a spot in the header, but would likely be used infrequently (If you have any analytics data on your footer links usage, that might be helpful).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also think changing the Technology link/page to ‘Developers’ is strategic. Technology seems limiting and apersonal, whereas ‘Developers’ is directed at a group of individuals and more clearly can contain a broad set of content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then familiarized myself with Eli’s existing work. Below is Eli’s header, which organizes the ways you can narrow your shopping experience on the left, with app functionalities (account, favorites, search) on the left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://hivemind.works/shopspring/img/headerSignedIn.png&quot; alt=&quot;eli&#39;s header&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my first pass, I maintained the layout that Eli set in his mockups, with navigation links on the left and actionable elements on the right. In the site map document I saw that the ‘shop’ elements were out of scope, but I chose to show what the design should show once these elements are added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://hivemind.works/shopspring/img/headerSignedOut.png&quot; alt=&quot;first pass&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tested this design on multiple backgrounds as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://hivemind.works/shopspring/img/headerDark.png&quot; alt=&quot;dark&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://hivemind.works/shopspring/img/headerBlue.png&quot; alt=&quot;dark&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://hivemind.works/shopspring/img/headerImg.png&quot; alt=&quot;dark&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still want to put more time into the button execution. I’m also interested in your thoughts on how I’ve chosen and organized the menu options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the first take at the main navigation’s execution completed, I turned my attention to the secondary navigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first wanted to experiment with using dropdowns as the secondary navigational elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://hivemind.works/shopspring/img/dropdown1.png&quot; alt=&quot;dropdown&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://hivemind.works/shopspring/img/dropdown4.png&quot; alt=&quot;dropdown&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While making these, I realized that they weren’t the best solutions. Since ‘About’ would have its own endpoint, a user would either need to double click (click to instantiate the dropdown, click to go to /about), or hover then click. Neither of these is ideal and I don’t think that surfacing the secondary nav in the header is very valuable. These links should always be present in the footer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I worked on excuting a secondary nav that would exist on the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://hivemind.works/shopspring/img/secondNav.png&quot; alt=&quot;2nd&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could use &lt;a href=&quot;https://aerolab.github.io/midnight.js/&quot;&gt;midnight.js&lt;/a&gt; to make sure that the links were visible, even without a background color/container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also began work on the footer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://hivemind.works/shopspring/img/footerLineHeight.png&quot; alt=&quot;footer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is &lt;a href=&quot;http://hivemind.works/shopspring/iterations/shopspring.html&quot;&gt;my progress on the working version&lt;/a&gt;, which includes work standardizing the scss. The code can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hivemindworks/shopspring&quot;&gt;on github&lt;/a&gt;. Let me know if you’d like me to make this repo private.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the work on this started, I’ll be able to iterate more and more quickly. More importantly I can get started with creative coding (adding &lt;a href=&quot;http://dvncan.com/work/2014/06/01/news-app.html&quot;&gt;‘finger’ elements&lt;/a&gt; to springs web experience).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 12:18:45 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://hivemind.works/shopspring/shopspring/jekyll/update/2015/04/23/navigation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hivemind.works/shopspring/shopspring/jekyll/update/2015/04/23/navigation.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
